Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Android Developer

@ hadilashkari@gmail.com

+34 645 86 91 03

Parcelona, Spain

github.com/hadilq

stackoverflow.com/users/2482947 in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

Summary

A curious developer with over 15 years of experience in software development, where almost 5 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student. An introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, and efficient apps to make the world better place to live.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with happy, creative, motivative and clever persons, so his talent becomes flourished.

He's interested in Data Science, Machine Learning, Functional Programming, Differentiable Programming, Category Theory, Math, etc. so constantly looking forward to learn thier technologies to use in Mobile apps.

Experience

Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey and one of the fastest growing one in the USA, Canada, and Norway with 15+ million app installed on Android devices alone.

- · After his first week of start, he could convince the professional Letgo team to allow him to jump right into the migrations of Kotlin, RxJava and Dagger.
- Fix a couple of bugs and implement multiple features and their A/B Testing

Technologies:

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room, etc.
- · Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD
- · Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco, Ktlint
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma, Firebase, Leanplum, etc.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

🛗 Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions.

- Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.
- · As functional manager of the Android team, he was responsible for the code quality of the Sheypoor app. He coached the team to practice design patterns, clean code, and using app architecture, along with updating libraries and adding new features with focus on agility and UX.
- Implementing new design of the entire app, including rebranding for summer campaign
- Improving the legacy code quality by adding Dagger and Kotlin.

Technologies:

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao, etc.
- Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD
- Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco
- Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Myket

m Sep. 2015 - Des. 2017

O Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users.

- Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.
- Implementing features such as handling deeplinks, search page, inbox page, etc.

Technologies:

- Dagger 2, Volley, OneSignal, EventBus, OrmLite, etc.
- · Agile, Scrum, Git Flow
- · Mockito, Espresso
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jfrog, Jenkins

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

O Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards.

- Implementing RFID card reader Android app via bluetooth connection.
- · Implementing Android and desktop apps.

Lecturer

at Universities

m Feb. 2012 - Dec. 2014

Mashhad, Iran

After two years of enrollment by conscription, he had been starting his work in two universities, Payame Noor University and Sadjad University of Technology.

Courses Taught:

· Application of Computers in Physics, Mathematical Physics, etc.

Article

Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow

Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin

ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern

ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava

ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events

Education

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

M.Sc B.Sc

in Physics in Physics

🛗 Jul. 2007

O Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/.. Butter Knife/ObjectBox/..

Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture MVVM/MVP/RMVVM

Principle

Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Design Pattern

Factory/Builder/Singleton/.. Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/ Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

Android test library

JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

Build Tool

Gradle/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool

grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/. adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Development Tool

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language

Java/Kotlin/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Rust/..

Operating System

Linux(Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

Special Honor

- Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in Physics at Spring 2007.
- Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor at 2018. Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin,
- Germany, March 2019.

 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW, Porto,
- Portugal, March 2019.
- Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain, May 2019.
- Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada, May 2019.

Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume in github Built at February 19, 2020